Guide to the Jack and Rebecca Matlock Papers, 1930s-2017 RL.11082
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1950s-2016; 1
  - Reagan and Gorbachev, 2
    - Draft folders: to work in elsewhere, 2001 (Box 22)
    - Draft folders: Reagan chronology, 2001 (Box 22)
      Research
    - Master copy, 2003 Feb; 2 folders (Box 23)
    - Draft, includes letter to Robert McFarlane, 2001 Jun 1 (Box 23)
    - Draft, 2003 Jul 24; 3 folders (Box 23)
    - Bound draft, 2003 Aug 1 (Box 23)
      Bound draft with edits
    - Draft with line edits, 2003 Aug 1; 2 folders (Box 23)
    - Draft, undated; 3 folders (Box 23)
    - Draft pages, notes, research, 1999 - 2000 Jan 16; 2 folders (Box 24)
    - Incomplete drafts, 1998 - 1999; 2 folders (Box 24)
    - Incomplete draft w/ edits, 1999 Apr 14 (Box 24)
    - Incomplete draft: Ch 2, 1999 May 22 (Box 24)
    - Incomplete draft + outline for Ch. 10, 2000 Jan 16 (Box 24)
    - Incomplete draft: Ch 1, 2, 2000 Jun 10 (Box 24)
    - Incomplete draft: Ch 5-12, 2000 Jul 26 (Box 24)
      Drafts, outlines
    - Incomplete draft: Ch 5, 2001 Jan 4 (Box 24)
    - Incomplete draft: Ch 5, 10, 2000-2001 (Box 24)
      Notes and research
    - Incomplete draft: Ch 5-10, 2001 Apr 23 (Box 24)
    - Incomplete draft: Ch 6-9, 2001 May 16 (Box 24)
    - Incomplete draft: Ch 8, 2002 Aug 7 (Box 24)
    - Incomplete draft: Ch 9-14, 2002 Dec 3 (Box 24)
    - Draft, w/ edits, 2001 May 16; 2 folders (Box 24)
    - Draft, 2001 Jun 26/May 31 (Box 24)
    - Correspondence and general notes, 2001-2002, 2004, 2010; 2 folders (Box 24)
      Correspondence including exchange with Archie Brown re: mss
    - Publisher correspondence: Random House, 2003 (Box 24)
      Correspondence
    - Reviews, 2003 - 2005 (Box 24)
      Printed copies
    - Incomplete draft: Foreword-Ch 3, 1999 Jan 23; 2 folders (Box 32)
    - Incomplete draft: Ch 5-12, 1999 May 15; 2 folders (Box 32)
    - Incomplete draft, 2001 Jan 13 (Box 32)
      Draft, includes reference material
    - Incomplete draft: Ch 3-4 (Russian Version), undated (Box 32)
      In Russian. Draft
    - Incomplete draft: Ch 6, undated (Box 32)
    - Draft (Russian version), 1999 Dec 11; 3 folders (Box 32)
    - Draft excerpt, with cover proof and poem about fountain pens by JM, 2000 June (Box 33)
  - Autopsy on an Empire, 3
    - Hinge of History: Reagan, the Russians, and the End of the Cold War, 1992 Mar 5 (Box 32)
      Draft, research
    - Came the Revolution! early outline, 1992 (Box 32)
    - Shattered Monolith, 1992 Mar 7 (Box 32)
      Draft with notes
    - Incomplete drafts, 1993 (Box 32)
      Drafts, notes
    - Incomplete drafts w/ edits and notes, 1994 Jan. 9 (Box 32)
    - Incomplete draft w/ edits and notes, undated (Box 32)
    - Draft w/ edits, 1993 Oct. 24; 5 folders (Box 32)
    - Draft w/ edits, 1993 Nov.-1994 Feb. (Box 32)
    - Draft binder, 1994 Jul.; 2 folders (Box 32)
      Drafts, notes, research
    - Book cover proof, undated (Box 32)
      Book cover
    - Draft with edits, 1994 Oct. 4 (Box 33)
    - Drafts with notes, research, edits, Chapters 16-23, 1990s (Box 113)
    - Style guide, 1995 Feb. 27 (Box 32)
    - Russian edition reference material, 1997 (Box 33)
      In Russian. Copies, notes.
    - Russian edition - correspondence, edits, draft of afterword, 1997-1998 (Box 33)
      In Russian. Draft, correspondence, notes.
    - Japanese edition - correspondence, 1997-1998 (Box 33)
      Includes Japanese material. Correspondence, draft.
    - Preface to Chinese edition, undated (Box 33)
    - Correspondence and draft notes w/ editor Lynn Anderson and Random House, 1995 (Box 33)
      Correspondence, draft, notes
    - Random House correspondence, 1994-1997 (Box 33)
      Includes exchanges with other organizations re: speaking tour by JM to promote book, as well as proofs/corrections
    - Reviews and press coverage, 1995-2000; 4 folders (Box 33)
      Contains Lithuanian, German, Russian, and Italian material. Also includes Matlock's responses and a draft of the afterword. Published copies.
    - Serbian press coverage, 1996 (Box 33)
      In Serbian. Published copies.
    - Correspondence and general notes, 1996-2012 (Box 33)
  - Other works by JM, 4
    - In Bed with Beria, 2011-2015; 3 folders (Box 33)
      Drafts, notes for unfinished novel.
    - Fateful Choices, 2004 (Box 33)
      Outline
    - America's Primacy: How We are Losing It and How We Might Keep It, 2006 (Box 33)
      Outline and notes
    - The Lion in Winter (translation by JM), approximately 1981 (Box 33)
      Includes drafts in Russian
    - Unknown draft, incomplete, undated (Box 33)
    - Superpower Illusions/Distorting History drafts, 2008-2009; 8 folders (Box 33, Box 113)
      Includes drafts, peer review, other notes for unfinished work
  - Spaso House, 5
    - Diary entries for use in memoir, 1990 (Box 34)
    - General correspondence and notes, 1991 Feb.-Sept. (Box 34)
    - Planning and notes, undated; 2 folders (Box 34)
    - Proposal, undated (Box 34)
    - Research, undated (Box 34)
      Includes Russian
    - Table of Contents, undated (Box 34)
    - Incomplete chapter drafts, 1990-1994 and undated; 10 folders (Box 34)
      Includes notes, corrections, and drafts from assorted chapters
    - Draft with edits, 1995 May 7; 2 folders (Box 34)
    - At Spaso House memoir (Digital-materials RL11082-SET-001)
      Digital file of RM memoir which provides a detailed reminiscence of the Matlocks' experiences leading up to and including Jack Matlock's appointment as U.S. Ambassador to the Soviet Union, and related political events in the world from the 1960s to late 1991, when the Soviet Union was officially ended and Gorbachev resigned as President. The book was published in Russian in 2004 as "Spaso-Khaus: li︠u︡di i vstrechi: zapiski zheny amerikanskogo posla." Many events narrated by Rebecca Matlock in her book relate to the photographs housed in the Rebecca Matlock Photographs collection, especially the series Russia and Other Regions.
  - Other works by RM, 6
    - The Day essay, 1950s? (Box 34)
      Drafts and notes
    - Story and article ideas, 1950s-1965; 2 folders (Box 34)
    - Creative writings, excerpts, poetry, undated (Box 34)
      Drafts; author unclear
    - Pushkin and Shakespeare, 1950 Jan-Apr.; 3 folders (Box 34)
      Class paper and subsequent revisions for essay contest
    - Family Trip, 1960s (Box 34)
      Account and description of drive from Accra to Lagos to Togo, etc. (author unclear)
    - Jim has a birthday, 1955 July 1 (Box 34)
      Correspondence, draft, outline for Photography Magazine
    - A Week and Two Days in a Soviet Maternity Hospital, 1963; 2 folders (Box 34)
      Drafts of RM's account of Joe's birth, includes photograph
    - The American Consulate, 1980s (Box 34)
      Draft with corrections recounting Matlock's arrival at Dar es Salaam and Zanzibar, 1967
    - Loose and unsorted memoir pages of living in Zanzibar, 1980s (Box 34)
    - A Brief History of Spaso House, 1989 (Box 34)
    - Sarah Caldwell's Challenges: A Memoir of My Life with Opera, 2008 (Box 34)
      Written with RM. Published volume.
    - Water Everywhere, 2008 (Box 34)
    - The Astronauts, the Cosmonauts, and the Matlocks, 2009 (Box 34)
      Includes undated autographed souvenir photograph of Yury Romanenko, Soviet cosmonaut.
    - Underway, 2010 (Box 34)
    - Some of Our Favorite Things, undated (Box 34)
    - Where We Have Lived, 2015 (Box 34)
    - Journal pages, 1950s (Box 35)
      Includes lists, notes, drafts, and some journal entries
    - Focus: photography exhibit introduction drafts, 2000s (Box 35)
  - RM Dear Everybody Letters, 7
    - Dear Everybody letters, 1981-1983 (Box 35)
      RM letters while in Moscow, Prague
    - Dear Everybody letters, 1987-1992; 6 folders (Box 35)
      RM letters while in Moscow
    - Dear Everybody letters, 1997, 2017; 2 folders (Box 35)
- Events, 1991-2016; 1
  The Events series documents JM's activities post-retirement, including his participation in numerous conferences, panels, working groups, and seminars at a wide range academic institutions, non-profit organizations, and corporations. This series is arranged chronologically, with files for events having significant amounts of materials, and general files for each year with additional miscellaneous materials. Events files contain speech notes, logistics and travel information, reimbursement or stipends, programs and agendas for different conferences, JM's notes and correspondence about the event or participating speakers, and other souvenirs or collected items from the event or his trip there.
  - General events, 1991 Aug.-Dec. (Box 93)
  - Loose speech notes by JM, 1991 (Box 93)
  - Politics, Economics, and Western Policy in the Post-Communist Era, Aspen Institute conference, Budapest, 1991 Aug. 24-31 (Box 93)
  - Science Applications International Corp. seminar re: nuclear weapons, 1991 Aug. 27 (Box 93)
  - World Order conference, Claremont University, 1991 Oct. (Box 93)
    With photographs
  - J.P. Morgan Investment forums, New York, Chicago, Los Angeles, 1991 Nov. 18-21 (Box 93)
  - General events, 1992 (Box 93)
  - Loose speech notes by JM, 1992 (Box 93)
  - The Soviet Union? Sweet Briar College Winter forum, 1992 Jan. 8 (Box 93)
  - Trip to Moscow and St. Petersburg, 1992 Mar. 13-23 (Box 93)
  - Bilateral Space Cooperation with the Former Soviet Union, US House of Representatives subcommittee meeting, 1992 Mar. 25 (Box 93)
  - Dean's Day, Columbia University, 1992 Mar. 28 (Box 93)
  - Arden House conference on American-Soviet relations: After the Soviet Union: Implications for it at the US, 1992 Apr. 10-12 (Box 93)
  - Life in Moscow during the final years of the old regime: an informal conversation with JM and RM, Ohio University, 1992 Apr. 22 (Box 93)
  - After the Soviet Union: Implications for US policy, The American Assembly, Columbia University, 1992 Apr. 23-26 (Box 93)
  - Albright College commencement, 1992 May 31 (Box 93)
  - Trip to Venice, Salzburg, 1992 June 19-21 (Box 93)
  - Unitarian Church event, Petersborough, NJ, 1992 July 5 (Box 93)
    Questions from audience
  - Transnational Institute: East-West conference on The Renewal of Russian Spiritual Life: Its Relation to the Emergence of Democratic Institutions, Dartmouth College, 1992 July 8-11 (Box 93)
  - International Coordinating Committee for the Support of Economic Reform and Cooperation, place unclear (Moscow?), 1992 July 23 (Box 93)
  - The States of the Former Soviet Union: Consideration of the present situation, future developments and appropriate policies; Ditchley Foundation conference, London, 1992 Sept. 11-13 (Box 93)
  - Trip to Former Soviet states, 1992 Sept.-Oct. (Box 93)
  - America's Role in the New International Order conference, Davidson College, 1992 Nov. 8-10 (Box 93)
  - Doing Business with Russia: Financial Times conference, Moscow, 1992 Nov. 11-12 (Box 93)
  - General events, 1993 (Box 93)
  - Loose speech notes by JM, 1993 (Box 93)
  - Twentieth Century Fund conference on Future of Aid to the Former Soviet Union, 1993 Feb. 18 (Box 93)
  - Retrospective on the End of the Cold War, Princeton University, 1993 Feb. 25-27; 2 folders (Box 93)
    With transcripts
  - Ronald Reagan: The 40th Presidency, Hofstra University conference, 1993 Apr. 22-24 (Box 93)
  - International Committee for Economic Reform and Cooperation, Kiev trip, 1993 June 7-9; 2 folders (Box 93)
  - Emmy awards presenter, 1993 Sept. 8 (Box 94)
  - Between Russia and Germany: East Central Europe after the Collapse of the USSR (re: ethno-violence), 1993 Sept. 30 (Box 94)
  - Meeting of Experts, Warrenton, VA, 1993 Nov. 12 (Box 94)
  - Ethnic Conflict and Regional Instability: Implications for US Policy and Army Roles and Missions, International Security Studies Program conference, 1993 Nov. 17-18 (Box 94)
  - General events, 1994 (Box 94)
  - Loose speech notes by JM, 1994 (Box 94)
  - Nizhny Novgorod: A Russian Success Story?, Columbia University, 1994 Feb. 4-5 (Box 94)
  - Federalism and Management of Ethnic Conflicts: Global Comparative Perspective, Salzburg (IREX), 1994 Feb. 26-Mar. 4 (Box 94)
  - Aiden House conference on American-Soviet Relations: Russia after the Zhirinasky Shock, 1994 Apr. 15-17 (Box 94)
  - Political Succession in Central Asia: The Leadership Challenge conference, CIA, 1994 Apr. 29 (Box 94)
  - Our Post-Cold War World, UNC Greensboro commencement and honorary degree, 1994 May 15 (Box 94)
  - The Dynamics of Economic Development in the Central Asian Region (IREX), Urumqi, China, 1994 Aug. 28-30; 2 folders (Box 94)
  - The Nuclear Challenge to Global Society meeting at International Club, Washington DC, 1994 Oct. 4-5 (Box 94)
  - George C. Marshall Center lecture, Garmisch, Germany, 1994 Oct. 16-19 (Box 94)
  - Armed Conflicts and Diplomatic Crises, Museum of Television and Radio seminar, 1994 Oct. 24 (Box 94)
  - After the Soviet Union: A Difficult Transition, American Forum for Global Education, 1994 Oct. 29 (Box 94)
  - Message from Japan symposium, Tokyo, 1994 Nov. 7-9 (Box 94)
  - Preparing the UN for the 21st Century symposium, Journal of International Affairs, 1994 Dec. 6 (Box 94)
  - The Crimea: Post-Imperial Perspectives on a Regional Conflict, Harriman Inst., New York, 1994 Dec. 14-15 (Box 94)
  - General events, 1995 (Box 94)
  - Loose speech notes by JM, 1995 (Box 94)
  - Council on Foreign Relations study group on The Role of Regional Organizations in Peacekeeping and Conflict Resolution, New York, 1995 Feb. 28 (Box 94)
  - Building Industrial Partnerships in the Former Soviet Union, Ft. McNair symposium, 1995 Apr. 19 (Box 94)
  - Russian Capital Market conference, 1995 Apr. 25 (Box 94)
  - XVII German-American Biennial Conference, American Council on Germany, Berlin, 1995 June 15-18 (Box 94)
  - Aspen Institute: Aspen/Wye Communications conference, 1995 Oct. 5-8 (Box 94)
  - Harbour Group trip to Moscow, 1995 Oct. 13-18 (Box 94)
  - Colgate University, 1995 Oct. 24 (Box 94)
  - General events, 1996 (Box 95)
  - Loose speech notes by JM, 1996 (Box 95)
  - US-German working group on the future of NATO, American Council on Germany, 1996 Feb. 7-9 (Box 95)
  - Cold War Endgame conference, Princeton, 1996 Mar. 29-30; 2 folders (Box 95)
  - Nuclear roundtable, Stimson Center, 1996 Apr. 3 (Box 95)
  - Living with a Turbulent Russia, Baltic conference, Chicago's Harris School, 1996 May 2-4 (Box 95)
  - Rethinking Russian-American Relations, Carnegie Moscow Center, 1996 May 10-11 (Box 95)
  - Bilderberg meeting, King City, Canada, 1996 May 30-June 2 (Box 95)
  - The Future of Foreign and National Security Policy, CIA/State Dept., 1996 June 10-11 (Box 95)
  - Chicago Council on Foreign Relations, 1996 June 11 (Box 95)
  - NATO in the Midterm conference, Atlantic Council/US Dept. of State, 1996 June 13-14 (Box 95)
  - Establishing Democracy: Political Reform and Press Freedom in Russia and Eastern Europe conference, Washington, 1996 Sept. 19 (Box 95)
  - International Forum for Democratic Studies conference, Washington, 1996 Sept. 20 (Box 95)
  - West-West Agenda conference, 1996 Nov. 21-23 (Box 95)
  - General events, 1997 (Box 95)
  - Duluth-Appleton trip, Minnesota, 1997 Jan. 19-21 (Box 95)
  - California trip, 1997 Feb. 11-17 (Box 95)
  - Harvard trip (Boston, New York), 1997 Mar. 10-11 (Box 95)
  - Trilateral Forum on North Pacific Security/trip to Moscow, 1997 Mar. 23-28 (Box 95)
  - Future of US-Russian Relations, Duke University, 1997 Apr. 2-4 (Box 95)
  - Russia: Partner or Problem?, Wheaton College, 1997 Apr. 8-9 (Box 95)
  - US Institute of Peace workshop, Washington DC, 1997 Apr. 11 (Box 95)
  - East/West conference in Nashville, TN, 1997 Apr. 13-16 (Box 95)
  - Cruise and trip to Tbilisi, Georgia, 1997 Apr.-May; 2 folders (Box 95)
    Includes materials on Psycho-Social Rehabilitation Centre, Georgia, and International Center on Conflict and Negotiation
  - Fourth Freedom Forum delegation to Europe, 1997 June 6-13 (Box 96)
  - 850th anniversary of Moscow, in Los Angeles, 1997 July 27-31 (Box 96)
  - Program for secret executives in national/international security, Harvard, 1997 Aug. 17-29 (Box 96)
  - Ohio State Cold War conference, 1997 Sept. 26-28 (Box 96)
  - Trip to Washington, DC, 1997 Oct. 4-6 (Box 96)
    Includes journal
  - Senate Foreign Relations committee hearing on NATO/Russian relations, 1997 Oct. 30 (Box 96)
  - State of the World forum, 1997 Nov. 4-9 (Box 96)
  - American Philosophical Society, 1997 Nov. 14-15 (Box 96)
  - AAASS convention, Seattle, 1997 Nov. 20-23 (Box 96)
  - Understanding Nationalism conference, co-led with Ian Bremmer, IAS, 1996 Dec. 4-6; 3 folders (Box 96)
    Includes conference papers, logistics
  - Russia and the Outside World: The new agenda for the 21st century, Moscow, 1997 Dec. 11-15 (Box 96)
  - General events, 1998 (Box 96)
  - Loose speech notes by JM, 1998 (Box 96)
  - SIT client workshop in Carlsbad, CA, 1998 Feb. 12-15 (Box 96)
  - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace conference on Rethinking US-Russia Relations, Arlie House, VA, 1998 Feb. 27-28 (Box 96)
  - Musgrove Workshop, National Security Archive, St. Simons Island, 1998 May 1-3 (Box 96)
  - Understanding the end of the Cold War: An Oral History Conference, Brown University, 1998 May 7-10 (Box 96)
  - Trip to Central Asia (China, India, Uzbekistan), 1998 June-July (Box 96)
  - US-Russian Partnership: Meeting the New Millennium: Institute for National Strategic Studies, Washington, 1998 Sept. 16-17 (Box 96)
  - The Indian Sub-continent: Prospects for the 21st Century, Ditchley Foundations, London, 1998 Oct. 9-11 (Box 96)
  - General events, 1999 (Box 97)
  - Loose speech notes by JM, 1999 (Box 97)
  - Finch Lecture on World Affairs, University of Miami, 1999 Apr. 15 (Box 97)
  - American Philosophical Society meeting, Philadelphia, 1999 Apr. 22-25 (Box 97)
  - How can Russia Recover?, AP/Harriman Inst. conference, 1999 May 7 (Box 97)
  - Council on Foreign Relations lunch meeting with Anatoly Chubais: Russia's Economic Future, 1999 May 21 (Box 97)
  - Western Policies and the Crisis in Russia, Aspen Inst., Berlin, 1999 June 4-6; 2 folders (Box 97)
  - Society for the Historians of American Foreign Relations conference, Princeton, re: Kosovo, 1999 June 24-26 (Box 97)
  - Trilateral Conference: Russia and the West: A Relationship in Crisis, Berlin, 1999 July 6-8 (Box 97)
  - Glenwood United Methodist Church reflections, Greensboro, NC, 1999 Sept. 12 (Box 97)
  - General events, 2000 (Box 97)
  - Loose speech notes by JM, 2000 (Box 97)
  - The Thatcher Years: The Rebirth of Liberty?, Hofstra University conference, 2000 Mar. 27-28 (Box 97)
  - Redefining Diplomacy: New Actors, Tools, and Strategies for Managing International Conflicts conference, Washington DC, 2000 May 8 (Box 97)
  - White Sea cruise on Kristina Regina, 2000 June-July (Box 97)
  - Council on Foreign Relations: Lecture by M. Gorbachev (presided by JM), 2000 Sept. 6 (Box 97)
  - General events, 2001 (Box 97)
  - CIA's Analysis of the Soviet Union, 1947-1991, conference, 2001 Mar. 9-10 (Box 97)
  - RAND Business lenders forum, 2001 June 2-3 (Box 97)
  - White Sea cruise on Kristina Regina, 2001 June 5-15 (Box 97)
  - Cruise to Alaska, 2001 July 31-Aug. 20 (Box 97)
  - The Future of the Russian State: Liechtenstein Colloquium on European and International Affairs, 2001 Oct. 24-28 (Box 97)
  - General events, 2002 (Box 97)
  - SIT investment symposium, CA, 2002 Feb. 14-17 (Box 97)
  - Trilateral Conference: Russia and the West: A Revised Assessment, Washington DC, 2002 Feb. 21-23 (Box 97)
  - Center for Strategic and International Studies (CSIS): Does Putin Matter?, seminar, Washington DC, 2002 Mar. 4 (Box 97)
  - Liechtenstein Institute on Self-Determination: The Future of the Russian State, Triesenberg, Ltstn., 2002 Mar. 14-17 (Box 97)
  - Challenges to the Existing Political Structure of the World, Boston University conference, 2002 Apr. 11-13 (Box 97)
  - Black Sea Regional Security Program, Harvard, 2002 Apr. 25-26 (Box 97)
  - World Politics Forum, Princeton, 2002 May 2-3 (Box 97)
  - American Foreign Policy Council meeting, Arlie House, VA, 2002 May 7-10 (Box 97)
  - Nobel symposium: From Conflict Escalations to Conflict Transformation, Oslo, 2002 June 17-19 (Box 97)
  - Baltic cruise on Sea Cloud II, 2002 July 5-20 (Box 97)
  - University of Kentucky Libraries symposium, Lexington, 2002 Sept. 27 (Box 97)
  - Central Slavic Conference, Fulton, MO, 2002 Oct. 18-19 (Box 97)
  - International Symposium, Japan, 2002 Oct. 26-Nov. 2 (Box 97)
  - General events, 2003 (Box 97)
  - St. Andrews Security Caucus, Scotland, 2003 Mar. 15-21 (Box 97)
  - Trip to Peru, 2003 May-June; 2 folders (Box 97)
  - Elderhostel Inc., University of Mary, ND, 2003 July 13-19 (Box 97)
  - World Political Forum, Turin, Italy, 2003 Oct.; 2 folders (Box 98)
  - AAASS convention, Toronto, 2003 Nov. 20 (Box 98)
  - General events, including speech notes, 2004 (Box 98)
  - Black Sea Regional Security Program, Harvard, 2004 Apr. 20-28 (Box 98)
  - Major Powers and Evolving International Order, Shanghai and Beijing trip, 2004 May 27-June 5 (Box 98)
  - Salzburg Seminar: Reinventing the West, 2004 June 13-21; 2 folders (Box 98)
  - Waterways of the Tsars Princeton Alumni Assoc. river cruise, Russia, 2004 July 14-27 (Box 98)
  - Senior Executives in National/International Security, Harvard, 2004 Aug. 25-27 (Box 98)
  - Greensboro and Durham lectures, 2004 Sept. 22-25 (Box 98)
  - World Political Forum, Stresa, Italy, 2004 Oct. 22-23 (Box 98)
  - Russian Studies symposium, Seattle, 2004 Nov. 17-20 (Box 98)
  - Off the Road lecture for National Committee on American Foreign Policy, 2004 Dec. 1 (Box 98)
  - General events, 2005 (Box 98)
  - SIT investment symposium, CA, 2005 Feb. 17-20 (Box 98)
  - How the Cold War Ended, Miller Center Forum, University of Virginia, 2005 Mar. 30 (Box 98)
  - American Committees on Foreign Relations conference, 2005 May 5-6 (Box 98)
  - 20th anniversary of Reagan-Gorbachev summit, Geneva, 2005 May 28-June 1 (Box 98)
  - Council on Foreign Relations National Conference: Iraq and Beyond: What should the US be doing?, 2005 June 9-11 (Box 98)
  - Russia: Political Kalaidoscope, Moscow, 2005 Sept. 2-5 (Box 98)
  - Trip to Boise, ID, 2005 Sept. 24-28 (Box 98)
  - British-North American Committee (BNAC), Philadelphia, 2005 Oct. 20-23 (Box 98)
  - The United States in the 1980s: The Reagan Years conference, Rothermere American Inst., Oxford, 2005 Nov. 10-12 (Box 98)
  - General events, 2006 (Box 98)
  - Putin and the Russian Tradition: Illiberal but Democratic?, Kennan Inst. seminar, 2006 May 9 (Box 98)
  - Baltic cruise: World Leaders symposium, 2006 June 29-July 10 (Box 98)
  - Black Sea cruise on Sea Cloud, 2006 July 10-July 22 (Box 98)
  - Implications of the Reykjavik summit on its Twentieth Anniversary, Hoover Inst., Stanford, 2006 Oct. 10-12 (Box 98)
  - Trip and lectures in London, 2006 Oct. 28-Nov. 6 (Box 98)
  - American Philosophical Society and lectures, Seattle, San Francisco, 2006 Nov. 8-15 (Box 98)
  - Human Rights Day, Boston University, 2006 Dec. 10 (Box 98)
  - General events, 2007 (Box 99)
  - Longwood University/Jamestown 400th, Hampden-Sydney College, VA, 2007 Feb. 26-27 (Box 99)
  - Russia and the Black Sea Area, Black Sea Security Program, Harvard, 2007 Apr. 24 (Box 99)
  - Navigating a Troubled World, Council on Foreign Relations national conference, 2007 June 7-9 (Box 99)
  - Ambassador conference, Russian Embassy, Washington DC, 2007 Sept. 23-26 (Box 99)
  - World Affairs Council of Connecticut, Hartford, 2007 Oct. 10 (Box 99)
  - Reykjavik Revisited: Steps Toward a World Free of Nuclear Weapons conference, Hoover Inst., 2007 Oct. 24-25; 2 folders (Box 99)
  - Trip to Moscow for State Dept. program on 200th anniversary of US-Russian relations, 2007 Nov. 5-10 (Box 99)